American Philosophical Society. Phillips Fund for Native American Research Collection 1960-present Mss.497.3.Am4
American Philosophical Society
- American Philosophical Society. Phillips Fund for Native American Research Collection (Box 1-30)
  - "Strangers in Their Native Land: American Indian Experiences in the Colonial new England Town" Includes reel of microfilm from the Samson Occom Papers, CHS, 1997; Fickes, Michael Lincoln
  - "Navajo Conversational Discourse", 1995; Field, Margaret
    Report (1p.) and DAT (Rec. 256) of two native speakers, Taft Blackhorse of Bitl'a Bito and Ernest Johnson of Gannada
  - "Thlewarle Mekko Shpkv Coko", 1971; Fife, Sharon A.
  - "O'odham Rhythms", 1994; Fitzgerald, Colleen Miriam
    (Diss.: Univ. of Arizona, 1997); plus report (1p.); "Degenerate feet and morphology in Tohono O'odham," Proc. West Coast Conference in Formal Linguistics 15 (1996)
    (F&S 4547)
  - Fogelson, Raymond, Fogelson, Raymond D.
    - "Report On A Summer's Field Work...", 1961; Typed field report (13 p.) on the Cherokee ball game, field work in Oklahoma, and comments on myths and formulae. Also contains 24 formulae written in the Cherokee syllabary.; Fogelson, Raymond D.
    - "The Cherokee Ball Game: A Study In Southeastern Ethnology" / Diss., 1962; 11; Fogelson, Raymond D.
      (F&S 601)
  - "Materials on Papiamento", 1964; Forbes, Jacques C. B.
    Images include color slides of Taino Indians, Curacao Island, of landscapes, dwellings, children, and market place, 1964.
  - "Women sachems; 1988", Forward, Jean S.
  - Foster, Michael K.
    - "The Iroquois Council-Speaking Tradition: a Close Linguistic Translation: 1990", 1994; Foster, Michael K.
    - [Iroquois vocabulary], 1991; Foster, Michael K.
    - "The Iroquois Council - Speaking Tradition: A Close Linguistic Translation (Phase 2)", 1994; Foster, Michael K.
    - "Iroquois Council-Speaking Tradition: A Close Linguistic Translation (Phase 3)", 1997; Foster, Michael K.
      Report (1p.); Outline of tapes (2p.)
      (F&S 604)
  - "Mohawk Color Terms. Nov. 1971", Frisch, Jack A.
  - "Life history; Sept. 18, 1979", 1982; Gabourie, Sophie
  - "Analysis of comparative Siouan dialects of Canada", 1964; Garner, Beatrice Medicine
  - "Spaces, objects, and figures in Navajo: from labeling to perception and cognition", 1970; Garrison, Edward R.
    (F&S 4560)
  - "Oneida Language Study and Databasing Project", Gick, Bryan
    Report (1p.); "The First Hundred Words of the Oneida Creation Story as Told by Harvey Antone"
    (F&S 4736)
  - "The Russian Orthodox Church of the Pribilof Islands, Alaska", 1999; Gielow, Donald L.
    Six 7" reel-to-reel tapes, 2 videotapes, 1999 (Rec. 244)
  - "A Theory Of Navajo Prayer Acts A Study Of Ritual Symbolism, Volume One" Diss., 1974; Gill, Samuel Dale
  - "Athabaskans Who Have Cree For Neighbors", 1971; Gillespie, Beryl C.
  - "English And Powhatan Approaches To Civilizing Each Other: A History Of Indian-White Relations In Early Colonial Virginia" Diss., 1992; Gleach, Frederic W.
  - "James C. Webber's 1928 recordings of Delaware songs and speeches from the F. G. Speck collection in the APS; 1970", Goddard, R. H. Ives, III
    (F&S 4215)
  - "Report on Iowa/Otoe Indian Language Dictionary", 1978; Good Tracks, Jimm G.
    (F&S 4177a)
  - "The Form and Function of the Basket Dance of San Juan Pueblo", 1968; Goodman, Linda J.
    (F&S 4836)
  - "Misc. Notes Of Penobscot Words And Materials", 1963; Gordon, Eugene
    (F&S 4659)
  - "Field notes on the Salt River dialect", 1980; Graves, William
  - "Primary Sources Relating to the Iroquois in the American Revolution", Graymont, Barbara
    (F&S 4392)
    Abstract: "The Border War: The Iroquois in the American Revolution"
    (F&S 4111)
  - "The Historic Development of Lakota Regalia, 1850-1920", 1993; Green, Adriana Greci
  - "Effects of Euroamerican Contact on Nunivak Island, Alaska", 1995; Griffin, Dennis
    Report (6p.); bibliography and oral history informant information sheets; tape index; 35 7" reel-to-reel tapes, 1995, 26 7"reel-to-reel tapes, 1996 (Rec. 252)
  - "We, the People of Kwigiumpainukamiu", 1990; Griffin, Eve
  - "Cheyenne Rank", 1987; Guerrier, William
  - " The Colonial Transformation of Mohawk Iroquois Society" Diss., 1986; Guldenzopf, David B.
  - "Report on Grant", 1969; Gunther, Erna
  - "A Political History of the CreekConfederacy, 1540-1763", 1998; Hahn, Steven C.
  - Hale, Kenneth, Kenneth L. Hale, (Kenneth Locke), 1934-2001
    - "Pima-Papago Recording Transcriptions", 1961-2; Kenneth L. Hale, (Kenneth Locke), 1934-2001
    - "Lexical Variability In Pima-Papago", 1962; Kenneth L. Hale, (Kenneth Locke), 1934-2001
      (F&S 2958)
  - Halpern, Abraham M.
    - "Linguistic-cultural situation on the Yuma Indian Reservation", 1976; Halpern, Abraham M.
    - "Coyote and Quail", 1978; Halpern, Abraham M.
      (F&S 4698a)
    - "Sex Differences in Quechan Narration", 1980; Halpern, Abraham M.
  - "Report on Work Done on the Navaho", 1967; Hammond, Blodwen; Shepardson, Mary
    Images include black and white photgraphs, ink sketches, of the Navajo Moutain community, individual portraits, genealogical chart.
    (Freeman guide 4652)
    - Elsa Liza Greymountain, 1868-1962, 1965
    - Jackson Greymountain, 1904-, 1965
  - Hamp, Eric P.
    - "Report on study for the Quileute language: and, ethno-botanical terms in the Quileute language", 1970; Hamp, Eric P.
      (F&S 4695)
    - "Quileute Recordings...", 1971; Hamp, Eric P.
      (F&S 4694)
  - "A study in mutual intelligibility and linguistic separation among five Siouan languages", 1970; Harbeck, Warren A.
    (F&S 4204)
  - Hardman-de-Bautista, M.J., Hardman-de-Bautista, M. J.
    - "Letter to Mrs. Gertrude D. Hess; June 16, 1970", Hardman-de-Bautista, M. J.
      (F&S 4120)
    - "Reconstruction of Jaqi personal verbal suffixes", 1970; Hardman-de-Bautista, M. J.
      (F&S 4121)
    - "Kawki texts", 1970; Hardman-de-Bautista, M. J.
      (F&S 4119a)
  - Harkin, Michael
    - "Ethnohistory of the Heiltsuk", 1988; Harkin, Michael
    - Nuu-Chah-Nulth fieldwork, 1996; Harkin, Michael
      (F&S 2959)
  - "History of the Queen Charlotte Islands", Harrison, Charles
  - "Ghost Dance-Era Songs of the Arapaho Crow Dance", 1995; Hatton, Orin T.
    Reports; transcriptions and musical notation for songs; Inventory of tapes of William C'Hair, Wayne C'Hair, Allan R. Taylor; five 7" reel-to-reel tapes (Rec. 242)
  - Field work in Choctaw Language, Mississippi, 1973; Heath, Jeffrey G.
    (F&S 4181)
  - "Missions to the Ojibwa of Sault Ste. Marie in the Nineteenth Century", 1997; Hele, Karl
  - "Some Notes on the Ytza, Quejache, Verpaz Chol, and Toquegua Maya; Nov. 1971...", Hellmuth, Nicholas M.
    Images include black and white photographs of text of Captain Valenzuela's conquest of Itza, 1695. Also, the conquest of Chiapas, Mexico.
  - "Narragansett Indians and Local Officials, 1800-1885", 1998; Herndon, Ruth
    (F&S 4498)
  - "A preliminary sketch of the morphology and phonology of the Zacapoaxtla dialect of Nahuat., 1971; Higgins, F. R.
  - Hill, Jennie-Keith
    - "A Transformational-generative Sketch of Two Problems of Navaho Syntax", 1965; Hill, Jennie-Keith
      (F&S 4564)
    - "Report on Research in Navaho syntax...", 1966; Hill, Jennie-Keith
  - "Report on study on Indian land cessions...", 1971; Hilliard, Sam. B.
    (F&S 4865)
  - Hiroko, Sue, Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - "Materials On The Hare Indians, Fort Good Hope, N.W.T. Canada", 1962-4; Linguistic notebooks and audio tapes of vocabularies, phrases, legends, songs, life stories in Slave, Cree, and Hare. Also, ethnological field research on the people, religion, history, life, economics, and social organization of the Hare Indians with accompanying photographs.; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
      Biographical/Historical note
      From 1961-1964, Hiroko Sue Hara conducted ethnographic and linguistic research of the Hare Indians of Fort Good Hope, Northwest Territory, Canada. Funded by the National Museum of Canada, the Northern Co-ordination and Research Centre of the Canadian government, and the APS Phillips fund, the analysis of her research findings culminated in her doctoral thesis for Bryn Mawr College, Hare Indians and their World (1964).
      Native American Images note: Nearly 1,500 black and white silver gelatin contact prints of Hare Indians at the Mackenzie River and Colville Lake, Northwest Territory, Canada from 1961-1962. Ethnographic images of tents, sleds, canoes, hunting and fishing equipment, utensils, native attire and accessories. Primarily field photographs of men, women and children by Hiroko Sue Hara with some prints of C. Osgood’s 1928 artifact collection at the National Museum of Canada in Ottawa. An illustration of the structures and activities associated with the temporary camp groups of this nomadic tribe. Referenced in the Supplement to Freeman’s Guide to manuscripts relating to the American Indian. Housed in the Photograph collection, call number 572.97 Sp3, Box 3, folders 24-35, Film 1175.
      Athapascan languages; Colville Lake (N.W.T.); Contact sheets; Fort Good Hope (N.W.T.); Indians of North America--Canada, Northern--Social life and customs; Kawchottine Indians; Mackenzie River Delta (N.W.T.); Sub-Arctic Indians
      - Fort Good Hope, Northwest Territory, Canada, 1961; 572.97 Sp3 (3-24); Black and white contact print of Kawchottine (Hare) woman and child outside temporary dwelling.; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
      - Kawchottine canoe, 1961; 572.97 Sp3 (3-24); Black and white contact print of a small Kawchottine (Hare) canoe at the point of Fort Good Hope, Northwest Territories, Canada.; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
      - Kawchottine moccasins, 1961; 572.97 Sp3 (3-24); Black and white contact print of Kawchottine (Hare) woman holding completed, hand-made moccasins, Fort Good Hope, Northwest Territories, Canada.; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
      - Kawchottine purses, 1962; 572.97 Sp3 (3-35); Black and white contact print, exhibit photograph, of three Kawchottine (Hare) purses with fringe, beads and feathers.; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
      - Kawchottine snowshoes, 1962; 572.97 Sp3 (3-35); Black and white contact print, exhibit photograph, of a pair of Kawchottine (Hare) snowshoes.; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
      - Moses sewing, 1961; 572.97 Sp3 (3-24); Black and white contact print of Kawchottine (Hare) man outside, sewing a large net for backing of moose hide, Fort Good Hope, Northwest Territories, Canada.; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
      - Mrs. Gully, 1961; 572.97 Sp3 (3-24); Black and white contact print of Kawchottine (Hare) woman sitting on ground fixing moose hide, Fort Good Hope, Northwest Territories, Canada.; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
      - Mrs. Gully boiling water, 1961; 572.97 Sp3 (3-24); Black and white contact print of Kawchottine (Hare) woman outside, boiling water in preparation for cleaning moose hide, Fort Good Hope, Northwest Territories, Canada.; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - "Report On Ethnological Field Research At Ft. Good Hope, N. W. T., Can", 1961; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
    - "Tables Of Contents For Record 28, Reels 7-19...", 1964; Hara, Hiroko, 1934-
  - Hodge, Carleton T., Hodge, C. T., (Carleton Taylor), 1917-1998
    - "Indian Summer", 1969; Hodge, C. T., (Carleton Taylor), 1917-1998
      (F&S 4350)
    - "Report on the Hopi dictionary project", 1970; Hodge, C. T., (Carleton Taylor), 1917-1998
      (F&S 4351)
  - "A Mandan dictionary; 1970", Hollow, Robert C.
    (F&S 4486)
  - "The Cushing census of Zuni", 1982; Holmes, Barbara
  - Hopkins, Alice W.
    - "The Good Message", 1981; Hopkins, Alice W.
    - "Mohawk narratives; 1983", 1985; Hopkins, Alice W.
  - "The Ties that Bind: Family, Gender, and Authority in the Old Southwest, 1770-1830", 1996; Hough, Jill
    (F&S 4555)
  - "Language and Ideology in a Navajo School Community", 1994; House, Deborah
    Report (1p.); transcripts of interviews (ca.450p.) with Benjamin Barney, Celeste Charley, Ferlin Clark, Donald Denetdeal;, Johnson Dennison, Edison Coldtooth, Alfred James, Anthony Lee Jr., Pauline Manygoats, Frank Morgan, Barbara Singer, Della Toadlena, Alvina Tsosie, Harry Walters, Renae Walters, and Paul Willets; 20 cassette tapes (Rec. 260)
  - "Dogrib field notes; July-August 1967", 1970; Howren, Robert
  - "Salmon tales: Intersections of Literature, Culture, and Environment on the Klamath River", 1997; Hoyer, Mark
    (F&S 4235)
  - "Report, field notes, and student papers on Cherokee grammar", 1981; Huff, Charles T.
  - "Plateau Indian Place Names", 1988; Hunn, Eugene
  - "Letter to Whitfield J. Bell, Jr.; December 5, 1971", 1972; Hymes, Dell H.
  - "Clause Combining in Hualapai", 1994; Ichihashi, Kumiko
    Report (1p.); tape index (1p.); DAT tape (Rec. 255) of Mary Jane Walema, Betty Wescogame, Jorgine Bender
    (F&S 4891)
  - "Poisoned by the Bad Fruits of the Civilized Tree: Cherokees and Alcohol, 1700-1907", 1998; Ishii, Izumi
  - "Ojibwa Discursive Practices at Sault Ste. Marie", 1993; Jackson, Deborah Davis
    Report (1p.); eight 7"reel-to-reel tapes (Rec. 263)of life history interviews with Ed Henderson, Florence Henderson Wells, Agnes Henderson Jones and Sam Jones; transcripts of life history interviews with Agnes Jones and Sam Jones and Agnes Jones and Florence Wells (47p.)
    Offprint: "'This Hole in Our Heart': Urban Indian Identity and the Power of Silence," American Indian Culture and Research Journal 22 (1994), 227-254
    Dissertation: "'Our Elders Lived It': American Indian Identity and Community in a Deindustrializing City (Michigan) (Diss.: Univ. of Michigan, 1998) (transferred to Printed Materials)
  - "Aspects of the grammar of Pima", 2004; 3.0 pp.; Jackson, Eric
    Project report (2 p.); correspondence with librarian (1 p.); release form (1 p.)
  - "The Ethnohistory of Yuchi Social and Religious Institutions", 1995; Jackson, Jason Baird
    Report (1p.); photocopy of paper: "Everybody has a part..." Florida Anthropologist 49 (1996), 121-130
  - "The Nez Perce Indian Reservation Community, 1892-1964", 1996; James-Stern, Elizabeth
    Report (1p.); 2 papers: "'To Promote a New Status for that Tribe': Archie Phinney and the Nez Perce Reservation" (12p.); and "The Nez Perce Reservation in the Twentieth Century: Adaptation and Identity" (15p.)
  - "Hopi workshop sessions", 1977; Jeanne, LaVerne M.
  - Research on Seneca language, 1978; John, Hazel V. Dean
    (F&S 4718a)
    (F&S 4351b)
  - "An ethnohistorical reconstruction of socio-religious change on St. Lawrence Island, Alaska...", 1987; Jolles, Carol Zane
  - "Report on fieldwork conducted in Tama county, Iowa, 1983" [Fox Tribe linguistics], 1985; Jolley, Catherine A.
  - [Field work/ Musical Roles/ Nez Perce Women], 1992; Jones, Judy, 1960-
  - "Phonological Variation in Oklahoma Cherokee", 1997; Jordan, Linda
    Ten 7" reel-to-reel tapes (Rec. 247) of interviews with Bobbie Blossom, Prentcie Robinson, Betty Sharp Smith, Polly Reed with Lucinda Turtle
  - [Research/ comparative religions], 1994; Kan, Sergei
  - "Navajo Complementizers And Semantic Subordination; 1974", Kaufman, Ellen S.
  - Fieldwork in the Menominee Language, 1999; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Brief report, 11 cassette tapes (Rec. 254)
    (F&S 4568)
  - Kealiinohomoku, Joann W.
    - "Hopi and Polynesian gesture codes", 1965; Kealiinohomoku, Joann W.
    - "Dance Data Guide", 1966; Kealiinohomoku, Joann W.
      (F&S 4293)
    - "Hopi and Polynesian Dance: A Study of Cross-cultural Comparisons", 1967; Kealiinohomoku, Joann W.
    - "Hopi Indian Texts: transcribed from records 52 ...", 1967; Kealiinohomoku, Joann W.
    - "Hopi Pottery", 1968; Kealiinohomoku, Joann W.
      Images include black and white and color photographs of Hopi woman, pottery, and pottery-making shed in Polacca, Arizona.
      (Freeman guide 4355)
      - Grace Chapella, 1966
      - Hopi-Tewa pottery, 1966
    - "The Folklore of Hopi Pottery Makers", 1968; Kealiinohomoku, Joann W.
      (F&S 4352)
  - "Yavapai Linguistic Material", 1974; Kendall, Martha Oaks (Burnett)
    (F&S 4866)
  - Kibrik, Andrej A., Kibrik, A. A.
    - [Database/ field notes/ Navajo], 1994; Kibrik, A. A.
    - "Transitivity increase in Athabaskan languages", 1994; Kibrik, A. A.
    - "Studies in Navajo transitivity marking and discourse structure", 1995; Kibrik, A. A.
    - "Studies in Upper Kuskokwim Athabaskan Grammar", 1997; Kibrik, A. A.
      Report (1p.); notes (142p.)
      (F&S 4353)
  - Kilroe, Patricia
    - "Videotapes of three Native American performers at the Indian Summer festival in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, September 11-13, 1992", Kilroe, Patricia
    - "On the Probable Origin of Plains Sign Language", 1993; Kilroe, Patricia
    - "Videotape of the second annual Indian Summer mid-winter powwow at the Mecca Arena, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, February 14, 1993", Kilroe, Patricia
  - "Glotaalization in Nuu-chah-nulth (Ahousaht and Ditidaht)", 2000; Kim, Eun-Sook
    Project report (1 p.); Full report, including elicitation lists and transcriptions (54 p.)
    Related Archival Materials note
    The recordings made as part of this project are cataloged under Recording Collection 273.
  - "Report and field notes on Koasati language; 1982-83", 1983; Kimball. Geoffrey
  - "A Study of the Structure of the Wenatchee Language", 1966; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - "Wenatchee-Columbia" books 1-3, 1965; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - "The development of Jalapa Mazatec voiced aspirantes", 1971; Kirk, Paul L.
  - Klokeid, Terry J.
    - "An introduction to the West coast [Nootka] language of Vancouver Island", 1972; Klokeid, Terry J.
      (F&S 4584)
    - "The West Coast [Nootka] Text Manuscripts held by the National Museum of Man and the American Philosophical Society", 1972; Klokeid, Terry J.
      (F&S 4585)
    - "The source of prepositional phrases in Nootka", 1970; Klokeid, Terry J.
      (F&S 4583)
  - Knab, Timothy
    - "Dialect Survey Of Nahuatl In State of Puebla", ca. 1970-1979; Knab, Timothy
      (F&S 4556a)
    - "Report. Aztecan language study", 1976; Knab, Timothy
      (F&S 4556)
    - "Mss. re. Indians of Mexico", 1984; Knab, Timothy
  - Knack, Martha C.
    - [Research/ original manuscripts/ Southern Paiute Indians.], 1994; Knack, Martha C.
    - "Philene T. Hall, Bureau of Indian Affairs field matron: planned culture change of Washakie Shoshone women", 1990; Knack, Martha C.
  - "Field Notes...Passamaquaddy...", 1975; Knecht, Laura
    (F&S 4642)
  - "The Writings of Cherokee Writer Ora Eddleman Reed", 1996; Kosmider, Alexia
    (F&S 4501)
  - "Kiowa belief systems", 1994; Kracht, Benjamin
    Correspondence between Kracht and APS, October 2002 (2 p.); 1 VHS tape
    The recordings made as part of this project are cataloged under Recording Collection 280.
  - [Letter to W. J. Bell; 2/28/78], 1978; Krech, Shepard, III
  - Research on Willie Ottogary, 1995; Kreitzer, Matthew E., 1957-
    The recordings made as part of this project are cataloged under Recording Collection 246.
    Report (3p.); informant release (1p.) for Clyde Ottogary; three 7" reel-to-reel tapes (Rec. 246)
  - Kroeber, Paul D.
    - [Field notes, Powell River, B. C., Canada. June 12-Aug. 16. 1982], Kroeber, Paul D.
    - "Thompson Salish Field Notes", 1989; Kroeber, Paul D.
    - "Thompson Salish Syntax/ Field notes; Oct. 1990-July 1991", Kroeber, Paul D.
    - [Field Notes/ Thompson (Salish) language], 1994; Kroeber, Paul D.
    - "Field materials/ July-Aug. 1985", 1986; Kroeber, Paul D.
    - [Thompson Salish], 1992; Kroeber, Paul D.
    - Thompson Salish fieldwork, 1995; Kroeber, Paul D.
      Field notebooks 16 (summer 1995, 105p.) and 17 (summer 1996, 155p.)
  - "Coyote and Bullsnake", 1978; Kroskrity, Paul
  - "Capturing the Vanishing Race: The Photographs of Dr. Joseph K. Dixon" [masters thesis], 1980; Krouse, Susan Applegate
  - "Observations of Michigan Indians; 1967-68", 1968; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
    72 color photographs and slides of Chippewa (Ojibway) Indians performing native dances in Michigan, 1967. Taken by Kurath and others while conducting field studies primarily in Ann Arbor, and Lansing, include images of men, women and children in full native attire performing the partridge, snake, corn, swan, grass, corn-grinding, and dance to the four winds. Of note, an approximately thirty minute, 16 millimeter color film (Film 1257) of a Chippewa celebration in Veteran’s Memorial Park, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1967. Referenced in the Supplement to Freeman’s Guide to manuscripts relating to the American Indian.
    Dance--Anthropological aspects--United States; Eastern Woodlands Indians; Indian dance--Michigan; Indians of North America--Michigan; Ojibwa dance; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Photographs; Slides.
    - Corn grinding dance, 1967
    - Jack Neyome, 1967
    - Partridge dance, 1967
    - Swan dance, 1967
    - Victory round, 1967
  - "Report On Comparative Study of Diegueno Dialects", 1970; Langdon, Margaret, 1926-2005
    (F&S 4233)
  - "Our Past in Our Future: A History of Cheslatta T'en Culture, Territory and Socioeconomic Relations Since the Fur Trade", 1999; Larsen, Soren
    (F&S 4838b)
  - [Cheyenne Texts]; 1985, Leman, Wayne
  - LeSourd, Phillip S., LeSourd, Philip S.
    - "Passamaquoddy", 1977; LeSourd, Philip S.
    - "Passamaquody field notes", 1978; LeSourd, Philip S.
      (F&S 4642b)
  - "Religion, Encounter, and Community in French and Indian North America", 1999; Levealle, Tracy Neal
    Includes CD of documents preserved in the Archivum Romanum Societatis Iesu (ARSI)
    (F&S 4642a)
  - "The Last of The Comancheros: The Decline of Inter-Ethnic Trade On The Southern High Plains", 1992; Levine, Frances; Merian, Thomas W.
  - "Ethnographic consequences of Sir John Franklin's northern explorations", 1965; Libby, Dorothy
  - [Yuchi Phonology], 1995; Linn, Mary S.
  - "Inverse Marking in Karok: The Function of the Suffix ap", 1989; Macaulay, Monica Ann
  - "Nineteenth-century History of the Penobscot Indians of Old Town, Maine", 1992; MacDougall, Pauleena M.
    Report (2p.); 4 cassette tapes (Rec. xxx) of interviews with Roy Dana, Sr., Madeline Shay, Theodore Norris Mitchell, Rose Scribner; partial transcript of tapes (29p.); paper: "Indian Island, Maine: A Nineteenth Century History of the Penobscot Indians" (vi, 378p.)
    (F&S 4114)
  - "Pilot Study of Hupa Color Categories...", 1993; MacLaury, Robert E., 1944-
  - "Oral History Transcript of Flore Lekanof Pribilof Aleut Relocated and Interned during World War II", 1992; Madden, Ryan
  - "Cultures in Collision: The 1891/92 Tour of Britain by Buffalo Bill's Wild West, and its Continuing Legacy" (1p. report), 1998; Maddra, Sam
  - "Acoma Texts (Keresan)", 1963; Maring, Joel
  - "Negro Indians", 1971; Marriott, Alice Lee, 1910-1992; Rachlin, Carol K.
    (F&S 4614)
  - Semantic relations in Hopi, 1970; Masayesva, LaVerne
    Report (1p.), 1970.
    (F&S 4439)
  - Masthay, Carl
    - "Cochiti & Jemez numerals", Masthay, Carl
      Letter to APS (1 p.); Vocabulary sheets with Jemez and Cochiti numerals, sounds, and miscellaneous phrases (2 p.)
    - "'A Manuscript Comparative Vocabulary of Several Indian Languages,' by Thomas Jefferson", 1995; 1.0 item Project report (1 p.), Photocopy of Ms. & typed d. (72 p.); Masthay, Carl
  - "Case Particles in Moses-Columbia Salsih", 1997; Mattina, Nancy
    Report (1p.); four 7" reel-to-reel tapes (Rec. 250) of Elizabeth Davis, Matilda Bearcub, and Norine Smith
  - "Hopi Participation in the Formation of the Indian Art Market: An Ethnohistorical Survey", 1993; McChesney, Lea S.
  - "The Phonetics and phonology of Navajo and Jicailla Apache", 1995; McDonough, Joyce M.
  - "Conduct, Code, and Perception in Koruk Inupiaq Culture; 1976", McNabb, Steven L.
  - [Ethnohistorical Research on Southern Plains Military Societies...], 1994; Meadows, William C.
  - Melnar, Lynette
    - [Caddo language/ linguistic properties], 1993; Melnar, Lynette